<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SpecFRS.com - Solo Spec Coupe 2016 Scion FR-S</title>
    <description>2016 Scion FR-S campaigning in the SCCA Solo Spec Coupe autocross class.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 21:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 21:57:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020 Topeka ProSolo Results</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50063439002/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Conference calls before practice starts&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; alt=&quot;Conference calls before practice starts&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063439002_ae51b1e02e_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;Well that was a productive weekend! I left for Topeka Kansas on Friday morning after working for a few hours and stopped on the drive out for a few more phone calls that I needed to have. I stopped and went into two locations on the drive down, a QuikTrip in Wentzville Missouri, and a Chick-Fil-A in Blue Springs. The QT had no workers or customers (besides myself) wearing a mask. The Chick-Fil-A was still closed for indoor service and all staff were wearing masks while working the drive through lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50062623953/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;SCCA Covid Notices&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;SCCA Covid Notices&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50062623953_55de655c1b_q.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;I was able to get out to Topeka in time get the Falken RT660s mounted on the car and to get some practice starts in with the new starting lights that they have going this year. My first impression of the lights, they change everything. In the olden days for ProSolo, back before LED lights, I used to leave when the second light was &amp;ldquo;going off&amp;rdquo;. With the LED lights introduced in&amp;nbsp; the past couple of years, I would leave when the third light was coming on. With the 2020 version of the lights, I had to wait until the third light was on and then start the process of releasing the clutch to get the car to move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first pass at the lights I turned a .391 reaction time, where a .500 is &amp;ldquo;prefect, and anything less than .500 is RED.&amp;nbsp; My second attempt resulted in a .744, not red, but definitely not in the .5-600 range that I expect when I&amp;rsquo;m starting. My third attempt was a .575 much more respectable. I ended up taking 8 practice starts, and while I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really happy with them, I felt at least comfortable enough for the weekend that I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday night I took the car by the car wash, grabbed a Vegan Lifestyle bowl from Chipotle and ran around to a couple of liquor stores in Topeka looking to add to my whiskey/bourbon collection. Friday night I spent my first night in a hotel with social distancing and cleaning in place. The Hampton Inn had the rooms &amp;ldquo;tapes&amp;rdquo; off with a seal that said they were clean, if the seal was broken you knew it hadn&amp;rsquo;t been cleaned. The elevator had a sign outside of it requesting that only 2 people use an elevator at a time. Overall the hotel experience was great, except for the fact that it was completely full with pre-teens running around on Saturday evening, obviously a sports tournament of some sort brought a lot of kids in, without any masks to be found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50063439742/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Elevator Etiquette&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Elevator Etiquette&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063439742_606cb2d0b6_q.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-right: auto; margin-left: auto; float: none; display: block;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning I walked out of the hotel with the front desk person saying &amp;ldquo;stay dry&amp;rdquo;. I thought, oh it is just a little rain, then the doors parted and I saw that it was a torrential downpour. I navigated out to Heartland Park, going about 45 on the highway due to the conditions and the RT660s feeling a little skatier than I would have liked on the highway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting out to the event site, I was my usual self, the first person out walking the course. By the time I arrived, it was still raining and windy, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t the downpour from the hotel so I walked in just the rain jacket and flip flops for shoes. Went through one area where the standing/running water was a good 2&amp;rdquo; deep, but overall managed to not get myself too soaked. There was plenty of wind damage around the site however.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50063441072/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Saturday morning rain&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Saturday morning rain&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063441072_303dbf889f_q.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50062625818/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Saturday morning carnage&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Saturday morning carnage&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50062625818_81f98a1849_q.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50063184026/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Saturday morning carnage&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Saturday morning carnage&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063184026_1debc7c863_q.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning&amp;rsquo;s start was delayed due to lightning (as was Sundays) but by the time my group ran, it was pretty much dry, with conditions getting better as the morning went on. After the Saturday morning sessions I was sitting in 2nd behind Kinch out of Colorado. Saturday afternoon brought more of the same. I felt I was struggled on the right side course, where I felt a lot more comfortable on the left. Saturday afternoon I found .15 seconds on the left, and just over .3 on the right Saturday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first run on Sunday morning I started on the right and couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any time, but found about .17 on the left, putting me within striking distance of Kinch. My second right side run I hoped I would find another couple of tenths but struggled and was .4 seconds slower than my best attempt on Saturday afternoon. Going into the last right on the left side I was pretty sure that I had no chance, and was going to have to settle for second place behind Kinch. I was pleasantly surprised when I came across on my last run with another .13 second improvement, enough to give me a .052 win over Kinch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first ProSolo win.The car has won previously, multiple times, but for me, in twenty years of autocrossing, this was a first, and it was a blast! Winning your class in a Pro means you move on to the Challenge the second half of Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50063446212/in/album-72157714923533618/&quot; title=&quot;My first christmas tree trophy!&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;My first christmas tree trophy!&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063446212_73b19056a6_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was I believe my fourth attempt at a challenge, and likely the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve moved on passed the first round. I ended up paired up with James Harnish out of Arizona in the first round. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel too great about my runs, but he ended up hitting a cone and that gave me the padding I needed to move on to the next round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Round number 2 I was lined up against Craig Wilcox. I&amp;rsquo;ve known Craig since 2003 or 2004 when we both raced 350Zs in B-Stock. He&amp;rsquo;s out of KC and has multiple national championships under his belt, while I, have none. Sitting at the back of the line waiting for the round to proceed Craig started running around debating on whether or not he needed to get gas for his SMF Honda, I selfishly started wondering if that might not play into my own advantage. It didn&amp;rsquo;t. If anything it took me out of my game. I realized just before pulling to the line that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t set my tire pressures. After round one I had gotten out and check them, but decided to set them closer to running. By the time I realized I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually set them, it was too late, I was strapped in the car and they were getting ready to send us to the line. I tried to put that out of my head and just head on out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first run was once again on the Right side course. I fell asleep at the lights and left with a reaction time of .993 almost half a second off of the ideal reaction time, and three tenths greater than what I would consider acceptable. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel great on the run, but it is also the slower side that I struggled with all weekend, I came back with a 1.001 deficit, almost .5 on the light, and another .6 on the slower course, I felt like that math worked. Going into the left side run I knew I was going to need to push it, and Craig might back off knowing he didn&amp;rsquo;t quite need to push as hard. I left on the last run with a .623 reaction time and pushed as hard as I could to try to find time. I looked across to the other course as I came through the finish and I was quite a bit farther than Craig, I hoped deep down inside that it was enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Craig crossed the line the announcer stated that I had made up over 8 tenths, but not the full second I needed, so I was done and Craig was moving on to the next round against Kinch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the video of my best left and right side runs (Sunday morning and Saturday afternoon respectively). The left side run uses my GoPro Hero8 with stability enabled, on a fixed mount on the roof of the car. The right side run uses the same camera with stability, but on my rotating mount. I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t feel like there is a big difference between the two mounts with the &amp;ldquo;hypersmooth&amp;rdquo; enabled in the GoPro Hero8.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZZk2lKqEbd0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My drive home on Sunday was uneventful, changed tires, loaded up the car, and hit the road. I averaged around 32mpg between Topeka and St. Louis, getting home just after dark so that I could unload the car and see the family before everyone fell asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out additional photos from the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/albums/72157714923533618&quot; title=&quot;2020 Topeka ProSolo&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 Topeka ProSolo&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063439002_ae51b1e02e_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Autocross Settings:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Swaybar:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Soft setting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Swaybar:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Stiff Setting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Konis:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;0.5 turn from soft&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Konis:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;1.5 turns from soft&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;30&amp;nbsp;psi&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;29&amp;nbsp;psi&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 16:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2020-topeka-prosolo-results</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020-topeka-prosolo-results</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020 Solo Spec Coupe (SSC) Falken RT660 Tires</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The time has come, Falken has updated the tire for SSC for 2020 with their latest and greatest Azenis RT660. I&amp;rsquo;ll save you all the story about how there was testing in September (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stay for it), and how they were delayed getting to the states and you have the option of running either the RT-615k or the RT-660 for the 2020 season. All you really need to know is that the RT-660 is a much better tire, and highly recommended (required mostly) if you&amp;rsquo;re running the SSC autocross class with the SCCA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tires are still a great price for SSC (as were the 615ks), I can currently get them from Tire Rack shipped to my door (or favorite installer) for $549!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran my first local event on these tires 2 days ago, and I am still on a euphoric high from their performance and my placement at the top of the PAX/Index results. These tires are a huge upgrade over the 615ks. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the 615ks, I feel they served as a great tire for 2 years in the infancy of the Solo Spec Coupe class, but the 660s are so much more. They are sticky. They are fun, they are competitive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the rest of the 2020 season and have gone ahead and booked myself into the Topeka ProSolo this weekend in Kansas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a video from our fastest run, Run #6, at the event, using our JD1 Camera Mount with a new GoPro Hero 8 Black&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0sm0iK9IifU&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Autocross Settings:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Swaybar:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Soft setting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Swaybar:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Stiff Setting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Konis:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;0.5 turn from soft&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Konis:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;1.5 turns from soft&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;30&amp;nbsp;psi&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;29&amp;nbsp;psi&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2020-solo-spec-coupe-ssc-falken-rt660-tires</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020-solo-spec-coupe-ssc-falken-rt660-tires</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2019 SpecFRS.com Season up to Nationals</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BwS-GexFfU8/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BwS-GexFfU8/&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BwS-GexFfU8/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by SpecFRS (@specfrs)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-04-16T00:32:09+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 15, 2019 at 5:32pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where has the time gone? The 2019 season, at least Nationally, has come, and almost gone. The ProSolo Finale and TireRack National Championships are next week in Lincoln Nebraska, and SpecFRS.com will be there. But how did we get there? Let’s look back on the 2019 season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The season started out in with a test and tune in St. Louis on March 10th. To start the season off, Sean Greer was planning on running the car, so we took it to Family Arena and tried to work off the rust (from the drivers). We followed up the test and tune with a local event in St. Louis at the end of March, with Chris taking the win in SSC and Sean taking second, in the three car class. It would be June 9th before we had another local event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April brought the first ProSolo for the year, in Grenada Mississippi. Sean and I headed down through Memphis on Friday, stopping to buy some, only available in Tennessee, Jack Daniel’s bottles to add to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.CollectorOfJack.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CollectorOfJack.com&lt;/a&gt; site. Grenada had 14 drivers in the class, with 5 trophies. Chris took the 5th and final trophy spot with Sean taking third for the event, each of them besting the other on one side of the 2 sided ProSolo courses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next was Lincoln Nebraska in late May for the Spring Nationals Champ Tour and ProSolo. In the ProSolo there were 16 drivers, 5 trophies. Chris managed to take 4th, while Sean finished in 8th for the Pro. The Lincoln Champ tour had 14 drivers, 5 trophies, with both Chris and Sean finishing in the trophies. Chris in 2nd, behind Kevin Dietz and Sean in 5th. Chris managed to pull out his best runs the last run each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Lincoln, Sean was pretty put off by the car, and decided that he wouldn’t be running it much going forward. Chris jumped straight into the local event scene and found success in 3 of the next 4 events, taking the SSC class win in all but one. At event #3 Tom Sotitopoulos, who co-drive last year, jumped in the car for the remainder of the season. In event 4 he managed to best Chris to take the class win. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 4 more local events this year, as of right now Chris is holding down the class lead in points, and is setting in second place in PAX/Index for the year. With this difficult PAX number, it will be hard to take the index win for the year, but that is the ultimate goal, Chris trying to repeat what he did in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here we are, heading to Lincoln on Friday, towing the car down with a fresh set of Falken tires and the alignment reset our specs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing we’ve changed this season is to adjusted air pressures down a bit in the back, from 31/31 to 31/30. No other changes from the car as to what we ran for settings last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Autocross Settings used 2019:&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Swaybar: &lt;/strong&gt;Soft setting&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Swaybar:&lt;/strong&gt; Stiff Setting&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Konis:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.5 turn from soft&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Konis:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.5 turns from soft&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; 31 psi&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; 30 psi&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brake Pads:&lt;/strong&gt; Ferodo DS2500	&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 03:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2019-specfrscom-season-up-to-nationals</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019-specfrscom-season-up-to-nationals</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SpecFRS at the 2018 ProSolo Finale</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is coming 6 months (maybe more?) too late, but at least it is coming. The 2018 ProSolo Finale and Solo National Championships was a week of ups and downs for the team. The results were mixed across the board in terms of performance with some highlights and some down times as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off the week we arrived for the ProSolo Finale on Friday, got the car off the trailer and waited for things to dry so that we could get some practice starts in on a drying start line. Everyone was waiting for dry conditions, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if that was going to happen, so I went out and took some starts to try to get a feel for the brand new Falkens that were on the car. Teddy took a couple of starts as well before the mad rush of people. The car needed some decals applied before everything got started, but overall was ready for the week of events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning for the ProSolo Finale came with Teddie heading out in L4. She struggled on Saturday morning with red light and cone runs, but putting her fastest left side run down for the weekend on her 2nd attempt. I also went out with Red Light and Cone issues on my first runs on each side. On the 2nd attempt on the right side I laid down my fastest run, it was about 7/10ths off the pace needed for the class for the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday afternoon both Teddie and I were able to put down faster runs on the other side, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t quite make up the differences we wanted. Sunday morning it was wet and cold and barely anyone found time on the course, Teddie and myself finding none.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teddie ended up in 3rd in L4 (ssc) for the weekend, 1 out of trophies, but close enough to get into the ladies challenge bracket on Sunday afternoon. I on the other hand ended up in 14th place, out of 18 drivers, well over 2 seconds off the pace. To say I was displeased with my performance is an understatement. I spent the next few days wondering why I was going to stay in Lincoln for the next 5 days for the Solo Nationals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday afternoon was a definite bright spot for the ProSolo Finale, Teddie ended up in the Ladies challenge and performed very well! She ended up making it to the semi final round before being knocked into the third place bracket. She ended up taking Third place to help salvage the weekend for both of us! I also headed out with my camera and shot a lot of the ProSolo challenge, having the most fun I had all weekend behind the lens of my camera. You can check out some of the photos via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gallery links over on RainbowMarks.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/30715031998/in/album-72157701162224125/&quot; title=&quot;Ladies Challenge - ProSolo Finale 2018&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ladies Challenge - ProSolo Finale 2018&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1848/30715031998_f8bfc33bb7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 04:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/specfrs-at-the-2018-prosolo-finale</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/specfrs-at-the-2018-prosolo-finale</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>Toyota</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Exceptional Results in Lincoln Nebraska!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;SpecFRS loaded up for travel&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/40667948930/in/dateposted/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;SpecFRS loaded up for travel&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/878/40667948930_9690c26601.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, what a week! Last Wednesday I loaded up the SpecFRS onto a borrowed trailer and left St. Louis the following morning to drive to Lincoln Nebraska for spring Nationals, 4 days of racing. The drive out was uneventful, spent it trying to listen to old “The Forward” podcasts, I’m not a huge podcast guy, even though I used to have my own back in the day, but I’ve been trying to listen to Armstrong’s podcast from the beginning, long drives are about the only time I can actually listen to it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  I arrived in Lincoln with plenty of time to get the car unloaded, teched, and over to practice starts to work on my lights for the weekend. I found the practice useful as I was able to knock down some Red Light issues that I had in Blytheville to only one RL all weekend in Lincoln. Friday morning, I talked Joe Tharpe into hoping into the car for the ProSolo as his C5 Z06 was out of commission due to a brake master cylinder failure. It was quite the change for him, hoping into a slow 4cyl, but he made the best of it all weekend! Joe finished in 7th in SSC for the ProSolo, only 1.4 back from the lead in the class. With Spec being such tight competition it is easy to be a number of spots back, but close to the leader. I don’t know that Joe will be ditching his SSP Corvette anytime soon, but I think he had fun running in a car with half the horse power for a few days. Unfortunately on Sunday morning he took a spill while working the course and injured his shoulder, taking him out of competition for Sunday and Monday’s Champ Tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teddie Alexandrova drove the car all weekend in the ladies classes (L4 for the ProSolo, SSCL for the Champ Tour). She excelled! Friday/Saturday she ended up taking the win in L4 (her first ProSolo win), qualifying for the ladies challenge in the 4th spot. She cleaned up in the challenge and took her first Ladies challenge win as well! She had previously (Ft Myers Pro earlier this year) took the Bonus challenge win, so this was her first legit qualified challenge win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;2018 Spring Nationals Champ Tour&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/40667001870/in/album-72157697469944065/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; alt=&quot;2018 Spring Nationals Champ Tour&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1721/40667001870_2e4f273f96.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Champ Tour Teddie went out on day one and put 2 tenths of a second on the open class, and 3.6 seconds on the rest of the SSCL class. Monday, day 2 of the champ tour, saw her finish the win in SSCL with a 6.7 second margin over the rest of SSCL and a time that would have been 2nd in the open class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris’ performance to start in the Pro was not up to his expectations. He started Saturday morning with a cone and red light, so only 2 of his first 4 runs were clean times. Finding a little bit of time on Saturday afternoon left him in 4th or 5th place in the 10 driver SSC class. Chris went into Day 2 with hopes of moving up, but was not optimistic about being able to catch James Yom who was leading the class. In what was likely a first for Chris, he was able to put down his two fastest times in the ProSolo on his final two runs, and moved up into the 2nd spot, .244 back from Yom. This was Chris’ first self qualified Challenge entry as well, heading up against Brian Peters in the first round of the challenge. Unfortunately he exited the challenge in the first round down about a tenth to Peters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Champ Tour, Chris finished out day 1 way back, outside of the trophies, if you’ve ever seen Chris grumpy, it was one of those days. For Tom Sotiropoulos, also driving the car, Sunday was a great day! He went out on his final run and put a 1/2 second lead on the class. Monday the tide turned a bit. Chris went out on his first run and put down a time that would be 2 tenths faster than anyone else in the class (Tom put down the second fastest time), jumping up into the 2nd place position from 5th. Tom finished the day strong on his third run and took 1st for the event by 1.1 seconds. Chris ended up losing one spot to Matt McCabe, to finish third for the event, 1/8th back from Matt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;2018 Spring Nationals Champ Tour&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/41572898915/in/album-72157697469944065/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; alt=&quot;2018 Spring Nationals Champ Tour&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/893/41572898915_094fcf3219.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Autocross Settings used in Lincoln (no changes from Blytheville other than new brake pads):&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Swaybar: &lt;/strong&gt;Soft setting&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Swaybar:&lt;/strong&gt; Stiff Setting&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Konis:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.5 turn from soft&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Konis:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.5 turns from soft&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; 32 psi&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; 32 psi&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brake Pads:&lt;/strong&gt; Ferodo DS2500
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 18:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/exceptional-results-in-lincoln-nebraska</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/exceptional-results-in-lincoln-nebraska</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>Toyota</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSC kits reach 100 sales</title>
        <description> &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/solomatters-664-5448dc0d5.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/solomatters-400-5448dc0d5.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/solomatters-600-5448dc0d5.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/solomatters-664-5448dc0d5.jpg 664w&quot;&gt;

 
 &lt;p&gt;The TireRack has announced that they have sold their 100th SSC kit! I have some insider knowledge that says they sold it before the Spring Nationals, but the announcement just came out today via the SoloMatters newsletter (hey look at that screenshot, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chrishammond.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;who is that?&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
 
 &lt;p&gt;If you haven’t tried SSC out yet, you are missing out! This class is the future of Solo! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Spring Nationals, stay tuned for our write up, we’re still trying to get caught up, but it should be up later this week! &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 03:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/ssc-kits-reach-100-sales</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/ssc-kits-reach-100-sales</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2018 Blytheville ProSolo Results for SSC</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;SSC Cars in Impound waiting for the Challenges&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/26990079767/in/album-72157690612809440/&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot; data-header=&quot;true&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; alt=&quot;SSC Cars in Impound waiting for the Challenges&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/906/26990079767_9da6e5a1e9.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, WOW. What an amazing weekend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went into the weekend hopeful that I would drive the car well, and that I would be able to prove to myself that I can hang with the big dogs. I’ve been autocrossing for a long time (with a few gaps in between) and while I’ve had some spurts of random success outside of St. Louis, I have never felt confident that I could do it repeatedly. The idea of SSC, a Spec class in Solo, was very intriguing to me, as I wanted to try to rule out “I don’t have the right car”, from the equation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weekend started out with me leaving St. Louis just after 1pm due to a company all hands meeting. I ended up getting down to Arkansas Aeroplex in Blytheville just after 5pm on Friday evening. I parked the car and met up with my co-driver for the weekend, Kevin Dietz out of Washington state. We discussed if there was a chance to do practice starts, or take a shot at the practice course. The practice starts were wrapping up, so I quickly unloaded the car and headed over. We ended up taking 7 practice runs between the two of us, and found the car to be rather pushy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we debated what to do to try to correct for the pushiness. Kevin thought that we needed to try to fix it with alignment as we had already taken out all the front shock (set them at full soft). In my packing haste on Thursday evening I realized I forgot to pack my toe plates and camber gauge. Matt Hodges had set however, so we were covered there if we did decide to change the alignment. After much debate we decided that we wouldn’t change anything until after morning runs on Saturday. We went through tech, at which point I said hello to the other driver of the car for the weekend, Lori Gill out of Topeka Kansas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a few course walks in before sunset and then I headed off to Wal-Mart for the supplies I needed for a weekend of autocross, sunscreen, sandwich meats, drinks, ice and even a new cooler. Saturday morning started out with breakfast at the Perkins attached to the Holiday Inn, which took WAY too darn log for a serving of biscuits and gravy, I then headed to the event site and got a few course walks in on each side.&amp;nbsp; From there it was time to finish the final prep on the car, which included getting a few more of the required decals mounted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lori was the first driver up for the weekend, competing in L4, so I took the car over to grid to get her setup and ready for the 9am start time. Lori headed out and ran in L4 having a good showing for her first time in the car. When SSC was up in Group 3, I went out as first driver and had a red light on my left side runs. On the right side course I ended up with a cone on each run. That put myself in I believe 12th place out of 13 for the class. Even with that poor placement, I was pretty happy. I had fun driving the car, and without the cones and red lights, I was sure that I could hold my own in the car in the class if I cleaned things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin went out with the second driver pairings, and performed very well. He ended up sitting in the lead in SSC after the Saturday morning runs, and didn’t let that lead go all weekend. After the morning runs, and the performance of the car we decided that we didn’t need to make changes to the alignment and would run it as is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being the leader, Kevin was now gridded at the front of the class, and went out on his Saturday afternoon runs and improved on his times on both sides by .171. Me, being near the bottom of the pack got relegated to the second driver line, we decided to try setting the front shocks back up a little bit, so I turned them from full soft, 1/2 turn. I went out and on my first Saturday afternoon left side run and turned my two prior red lights into a coned run, but at least it was a time. On the right side I was able to clean up cones from the first two passes, and on my final run on the right side run make up more time. I managed to move up into 3rd spot, .056 back from David Lousteau, and .256 back from Kevin. Funny story, after my second left side run, I immediately headed to impound, I was stoked that I finally had a good run on the left and completely forgot that I needed to run one more run on the right. Lucky for me I was able to get back in line and get the right side run completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning Kevin and I both went out with the goal of improving things considerable. I was honestly hoping to catch him, and he was hoping to put down quick runs on his first runs to try and increase his lead on the class. He succeeded, I did not. Kevin managed to put his fastest times down for the weekend on his final run on each side. I managed to do my fastest on Sunday morning as well, but not near as fast as I think I could have been. Ultimately I finished in third place, a trophy spot, and Kevin took the win in the SSC class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of the day I was sitting in 44th qualifying position for the Super Challenge, the 32 car bracket competition at the end of the ProSolo event. I put my name into the drawing to get into the 8 car bonus challenge, but with all of the people who ended up dropping out of the Super Challenge bracket I ended up getting in as the 32nd seed. Kevin got in as the 6th seed I believe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Super Challenge&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; data-header=&quot;true&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/40959600555/in/album-72157690612809440/&quot; title=&quot;Spec FR-S leaving the Line&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/910/40959600555_7ac6e2412b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; alt=&quot;Spec FR-S leaving the Line&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the bracket competition, each car lines up and runs their Class’ dial in time, which for me, meant in order to be fast, I needed to run Kevin’s fastest time for the right side, and left side. To account for this, each car that lines up in the bracket has a unique pattern to the lights at the starting line. For a slower car, such as SSC, that means we would typically leave BEFORE the car we are lined up against, with the idea being that if we both ran perfect times we would cross the finish line at exactly the same time. My first time in the Super Challenge was not uneventful. I went out on the right side course, lined up against the #1 see, David Whitner. The right side course was slightly slower all weekend compared to the left side course, so when I came back, with an 8/10ths of a second difference from David I was pretty happy, knowing that I could probably make up that difference on the left side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When David and I lined up on the 2nd runs, I was on the left. The “christmas tree”, the drag strip lights that tell us when to start, started coming down, but they came down first for David, and not for me as they should. I immediately thought something was wrong, but I couldn’t risk sitting there and not taking a run, so I left when my lights eventually dropped. That run on the left side was sloppy, I was not happy with it, but I was pretty stoked when I came in from the run and was told to get right back in the lane for the left side and to take another run. They had entered the dial in times incorrectly, so they needed us to run the course again. On my second time around the left course, the car felt MUCH better. Problem is, I picked up a cone early on in the process. I still pushed to get the car back across the finish with a decent time, but I couldn’t make up the deficit of the cone and I was bumped from my first Super Challenge attempt in the first round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin ended up in the 2nd to last pairing out of the round of 32, lined up and defeated Chris Edens in an S2 Miata. The next round Kevin lined up against Russell Blume in his HS Mini Cooper and took him down as well. The third round was SSC #1 and #2 with David Lousteau lining up against Kevin. Again Kevin drove away victorious to line up against Mike King out of Florida, in his HS Ford. The final round had Kevin lined up against Jonathan Warlof in a blue Mustang. I can’t do justice with words the excitement I had of that final round, so I would encourage you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/christopherhammond/videos/10156457657654703/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;watch the video from my Facebook Live session&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;267&quot; height=&quot;476&quot; src=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fchristopherhammond%2Fvideos%2F10156457657654703%2F&amp;amp;show_text=0&amp;amp;width=267&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; style=&quot;border: currentcolor; border-image: none; overflow: hidden;&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the video from on top of the car of Kevin’s Super Challenge win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H97rPchYJ4E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Autocross Settings:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Swaybar: &lt;/strong&gt;Soft setting&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Swaybar:&lt;/strong&gt; Stiff Setting&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Konis:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.5 turn from soft&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Konis:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.5 turns from soft&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; 32 psi&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; 32 psi &lt;p&gt; &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; data-header=&quot;true&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/26990122027/in/album-72157690612809440/&quot; title=&quot;Challenge Winners&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/869/26990122027_c44c9d1814.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; alt=&quot;Challenge Winners&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 01:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2018-blytheville-prosolo-results-for-ssc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2018-blytheville-prosolo-results-for-ssc</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>Toyota</category>
        
        <category>Scion</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSC Contingency Opportunities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So one of the ways to help supplement the cost of autocross at a National level with the SCCA is to participate in their contingency programs. There are a variety of contingency options available, depending on:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What make of car you drive&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What class you run in&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What tires you run&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What programs you register for&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scca.com/pages/solo-contingency&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SCCA Autocross Contingency page&lt;/a&gt; to see which options are available to you, and which will work for your particular class/car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the catch with contingencies? Well, you typically (almost always) have to run your vehicle with the sponsors decals on the vehicle. &lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; data-header=&quot;true&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/39900291410/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Spec FR-S Decked Out&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/964/39900291410_b5302163bd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; alt=&quot;Spec FR-S Decked Out&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;For SSC, here are the contingencies that I believe to be applicable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;TRD – ProSolo&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Falken Tire – ProSolo &amp;amp; Champ/Match Tours&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hawk Performance Brakes - ProSolo &amp;amp; Champ/Match Tours&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soloperformance.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Solo Performance Specialties&lt;/a&gt; – Champ/Match Tours&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;RaceChick.com – ProSolo (ladies)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amounts will all vary, but Falken for example will pay $300 for first, $200 for second and $100 for third. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 02:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/ssc-contingency-opportunities</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/ssc-contingency-opportunities</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>Toyota</category>
        
        <category>Scion</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First event in SSC</title>
        <description>&lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Today was the first St. Louis Region Solo event in the 2018 series, so it was the first time out in the car, and I must say, it was great (albeit cold, windy, and even snowing/sleeting/raining at times)! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SGoV08aTlmU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Natalie&lt;/a&gt; got to take the first runs in the car, actually the first 6! She hasn&amp;rsquo;t seriously autocrossed since 2008 when we had the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.corvettez06.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Corvette&lt;/a&gt;, but I believe this year will be different and she&amp;rsquo;ll run quite a few local events and then we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can&amp;rsquo;t talk her into Solo Nationals as well. Natalie managed to get down to a 51.997 on her 4th run, but trying harder on run 5 and 6 she went the other direction on the clock. We&amp;rsquo;ll see where she placed within the ladies challenge once the results are published later this week.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot; data-header=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/41484915701/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Couples Autocross&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Couples Autocross&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/819/41484915701_c0dbb0aa1c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;My turn to run was the third heat, which surprising started just around 1pm or maybe a little after. (The STL region really had their stuff organized for event #1, definitely ran smoothly considering it was the first event of the year). There were 3 other drivers in SSC today in St. Louis, Michael Kopec and a gentlemen from Troy, IL who was out in his car at his first autocross! That takes some commitment, getting into autocross in a spec class right off the bat, hope to see him at more local events this year.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;My first run I went out an ran a 47.477, though I plowed through 3 cones after the finish (might as well get my own cone cherry popped on my first run in the car).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;My second run I went a just under a tenth of a second faster, but picked up a cone on the front portion of the course. My 3rd 4th and 5th runs ended up getting faster, each separated by a couple of hundredths. I was ultimately able to get my fastest clean time down to 46.497, .832 ahead of Kopec for the day.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a video from my fastest run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HtN1BvhQrfI&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Front Swaybar: Soft setting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rear Swaybar: Stiff Setting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Front Konis: 1 turn from soft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rear Konis: 1.5 turns from soft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Front Tire Pressure: 35 psi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rear Tire Pressure: 34 psi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my 6th run the course was started to get slick due to the rain/sleet, and I ended up losing control on the back half of the course. On the way home the car felt funky, so I stopped and took the turns out of the Konis. I ended up noticing that the steering wheel was off center, and then I noticed that both the ABS and SLIP lights were on the dash. I scanned the OBD2 with my Torque app to see if there were any codes being thrown for those two lights, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find anything. My internet research, and help from the SSC group on Facebook leads me to believe that the alignment (wheel being crooked) is what is causing the lights. I&amp;rsquo;ll head over to SPS this week and see what I screwed up when I spun today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I&amp;rsquo;m stoked about how much fun I had in the car today. I didn&amp;rsquo;t win PAX, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to, the PAX for this class doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be close to a valid equalizer for 2018. I will be surprised if I get in the top 2 on PAX at all this year locally, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised.&amp;nbsp; I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the Misfit Toys event next weekend, and the Blytheville ProSolo the following weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; 

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 02:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/first-event-in-ssc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/first-event-in-ssc</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>Scion</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Autocross alignment in St. Louis Missouri</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the parts installed on the car, it was time to get wheels and tires mounted/balanced and installed. I also needed to get an alignment on the car as I knew it wasn’t close to the autocross specs that Tire Rack had in their recommendations. So I took my car to the only place I trust for an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soloperformance.com/alignment&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;autocross alignment&lt;/a&gt; in Missouri, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soloperformance.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Solo Performance Specialties&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tires mounted up nice and easy on the Konig Ampliforms, after I got the wheels with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://specfrs.com/Blog/aid/6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;right bolt pattern of course&lt;/a&gt;. They were mounted onto the car and it was up on to the alignment rack next. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; data-header=&quot;true&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/39569348460/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;SpecFRS.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/889/39569348460_4f34229364_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;SpecFRS.com&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dave at Solo Performance knows his stuff, so he was able to get the car setup as recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alignment Specs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Front Camber: -3 degrees&lt;br&gt;Front Caster: 5.4 degrees&lt;br&gt;Front Toe: 0 inches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rear Camber: –2.25 degrees&lt;br&gt;Rear Toe: 1/8” toe in &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; data-header=&quot;true&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot;  href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/27530585808/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;SpecFRS.com Alignment&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/792/27530585808_1fe8647719_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;SpecFRS.com Alignment&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is the first St. Louis region autocross on April 15th. There are 3 SSC cars entered, so let’s see how this thing (and mainly this driver) does! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 03:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/autocross-alignment-in-st-louis-missouri</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/autocross-alignment-in-st-louis-missouri</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>Scion</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Install</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
