<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SpecFRS.com - Solo Spec Coupe 2016 Scion FR-S</title>
    <description>2016 Scion FR-S campaigning in the SCCA Solo Spec Coupe autocross class.</description>
    <link>https://www.specfrs.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.specfrs.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 16:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 16:24:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Year Later</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soloperformance.com&quot;&gt;Solo Performance Specialties&lt;/a&gt; is your one stop shop for all your autocross needs. They have a huge selection of tires, wheels, and suspension parts.  They are located in St. Louis, MO, but they ship all over the country. They are a great resource for all your autocross needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for Race Gear in St. Louis, &lt;a href=&quot;https://soloperformance.com/pages/find-us-service-info&quot;&gt;be sure to stop by the SPS at their retail location&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 10:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.specfrs.com/race-gear-in-st-louis</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.specfrs.com/race-gear-in-st-louis</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
        <category>Accident</category>
        
        <category>Supplies</category>
        
        <category>Gear</category>
        
        <category>St. Louis</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Year Later</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I realized a couple of days ago that it had been 12 months since the FR-S met its unfortunate demise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only autocrossed once since then, in Dave’s Mustang at the 2021 Solo Nationals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s going to change though. I’ve got the bug. I need to find a ride. I need a project car, I need a toy. Sometime later this year the FR-S will be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FR-S ended up going north, I think towards Minneapolis. The guy who purchased it owns a body shop, I was told it would end up being a track car, but I haven’t seen any progress pictures on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 10:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.specfrs.com/one-year-later</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.specfrs.com/one-year-later</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
        <category>Accident</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Parting out the Scion FR-S</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The time has finally come, time that I finally have, to try to start getting the 2016 Scion FR-S parted out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I got the car unburried from the smaller side of the garage and pulled it into the bigger 2 car bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, I got the car up on jackstands, after finding the wheel lock, and took the Konig wheels off the car. David Z picked those up from me yesterday afternoon, so the wheel and tires from the car are gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up I will be taking the SSC suspension bits, and the nameless exhaust, and replace them with the OEM parts. Once I have those off, hopefully in the next week, I’ll be selling those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things I need to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;need to get to the DMV and get the lean cleared off the title so I can easily part with the car/title.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;decide how much of what was removed will be put back on the car (front/rear bumper, lights, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in any of the car, or SSC bits, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Car is located in Wildwood Missouri, just outside of St. Louis. The motor has less than 45k miles on it and runs great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 10:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.specfrs.com/parting-out-the-frs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.specfrs.com/parting-out-the-frs</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
        <category>Accident</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Autocross Crash and Why You Need Autocross Insurance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there, long time no see…. Where has SpecFRS gone? Well here’s the story of how my autocross car came to a very sad demise, and a couple of tips for you on how to not have it happen to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost: Look into Autocross insurance. Lockton Motorsports provides insurance options that cover cars DURING autocross events, you should definitely &lt;a href=&quot;https://locktonmotorsports.com/autocross-off-track/&quot;&gt;check them out&lt;/a&gt;. It is very likely that your normal street car insurance policy will NOT cover you, and you asking them if they do may even cause red flags to be raised. I did NOT have autocross insurance on my 2016 Scion FR-S, even though I had looked into it a couple of weeks before the incident, I didn’t pull the trigger (if memory serves, it was like $225 for the year for my car), and would have likely made 2021 not be near as bad as it ended up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-will-not-autocross-a-car-again-if-it-doesnt-have-autocross-insurance-i-dont-care-who-owns-the-car-lesson-hard-learned&quot;&gt;I will not autocross a car again if it doesn’t have autocross insurance, I don’t care who owns the car, lesson (hard) learned.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what happened? Well, this incident occurred this summer. I had taken my third run and put down a scorcher, my codriver went out and took his third or fourth run (don’t recall). I was standing next to a buddy of mine trying to watch the run when I saw the car get tail happy, due to where I was standing in grid I couldn’t really see the car/course very well. The car came to a stop and I thought, “oh he just lost control and stopped”. Shortly there after I heard a request for any first responders over the PA, I immediately knew something was wrong. I ran over to where the car was stopped, as I was on my way over I saw a course worker picking something up, I assumed it was a GoPro that had fallen off the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t a GoPro, it was the passenger mirror, or parts of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to the car, my codriver was either out, or getting out of the car. He wasn’t happy, but didn’t appear to be hurt, that was the immediate question to be answered, make sure he was okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we started looking at the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The car had impacted a light pole in the parking lot, scraping down the passenger side of the FR-S. The damage started at the front fender and went all the way back to the quarter panel. The majority of the damage was the passenger door, it was pushed in quit a bit, and didn’t look like it would open. The car would start and drive, so I got in and drove it outside of the course area. The wheel was definitely out of alignment, and had a LOT more play than it should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/6-13-2021/side-800-158409714.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/6-13-2021/side-400-158409714.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/side-600-158409714.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/side-800-158409714.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/side-1000-158409714.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The side curtain and passenger seat airbags deployed. There was glass everywhere, while the window was down, in the door, it had enough of an impact that the glass from the door and in the mirror, went everywhere. Getting into the car you had to be careful to avoid setting your hand down on something and getting yourself cut up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pole-800-1198c3df4.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pole-400-1198c3df4.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pole-600-1198c3df4.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pole-800-1198c3df4.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pole-1000-1198c3df4.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pole2-800-7f0e91a98.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pole2-400-7f0e91a98.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pole2-600-7f0e91a98.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pole2-800-7f0e91a98.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pole2-1000-7f0e91a98.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After parking the car I started trying to assess the situation. We threw a jack under it and removed the right front wheel. The wheel had some damage to it, after removal I found that the tie rod bolt was bent about 45 degrees. At this point I figured there was no way to safely drive the car home, so I began to figure out how to get it home. I called my insurance to get roadside assistance to pick it up, but ultimately a friend was driving through town with an empty trailer and he hauled the car down to Solo Peformance Specialties for me that evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that week I replaced the tie rod end, that helped bring the wheel back into some version of alignment, but not 100%. I ended up driving the car home to my house from Solo Performance a week or two later and parked it in the garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the car to two different locations for an estimate, ultimely we choose to go with a facility that friends had had good experiences with. They took the car and ordered a few thousand dollars in parts to try to get it ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They ended up digging into the car, cutting the fender and quarter panel off, removed the door, and gave me an updated estimate (we asked them to do that, dig in and let me know if it was going to be more costly than originally expected). Based on the updated estimate, we determined that it just didn’t make sense to repair the car to street car condition. I picked up the car and brought it home in November and it’s been sitting in the garage since, collecting dust. Currently the front and rear bumpers are off the car, along with the lights on the passenger side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This spring, hopefully sooner rather than later, I will be stripping the SSC parts off the car and seeing if anyone wants to purchase those. I will also be selling the wheels which have Falken 660 tires on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I will put the OEM suspension back on the car and see how much I can get for it. I really think it would be a good car to start a track/road racer build out of, but I simply don’t have the time or motivation to complete a project like that myself. The motor has ~42k miles on it and was very strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything but the passenger side of the car was prestine, so who knows what I can actually get for the car. I won’t be parting it out individually at this point, unless I find some car that I think I can easily throw the motor into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a track project car, feel free to reach out to me, let’s see if we can make a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pro-tech-800-ab1fafdc8.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pro-tech-400-ab1fafdc8.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pro-tech-600-ab1fafdc8.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pro-tech-800-ab1fafdc8.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/6-13-2021/pro-tech-1000-ab1fafdc8.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s next for me? Well right now I have an order in for a new Nissan Z, and a Ford F-250 truck. I have no idea when either of those will be built….&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 13:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.specfrs.com/autocross-accident-why-you-need-autocross-insurance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.specfrs.com/autocross-accident-why-you-need-autocross-insurance</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
        <category>Accident</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2021 Events 1 and 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So here we are, it’s 2021 already and you’ve hopefully started autocrossing again. We have had the car out to &lt;s&gt;one&lt;/s&gt; two events so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first event was back on April 11th, a few days before we started writing this post (and are just now getting around to finishing). Tom S is codriving with me at most events this year, not sure how many out of town events he will be at, or heck how many out of town events I will be at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;event-1&quot;&gt;Event 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So event one. The weekend before the event I decided it was time to take all the rest of the vinyl off (sponsor/series decals) and with that came a load of residue and blemishes in the paint from the removal. 2 days before the event I went down to Detail Garage in Valley Park to pick up some supplies. I grabbed a Torq random orbital buffer, along with a number of other supplies so that I could try my hand at paint correction. I spent Saturday before event one paint correcting the car (all but the back of the rear end). I must say, I was totally pleased with the results. You can see a before and after of the top of the trunk on our Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CNf5_xlFVbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;13&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CNf5_xlFVbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CNf5_xlFVbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by SpecFRS (@specfrs)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting the polishing done and throwing some wax on the car, I swapped the wheels/tires out for the set of brand new Falken RT660s and packed the car up to be ready to head out early in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event went well, though the car took some cone damage to the front end. I had removed the racer’s tape that had been holding some of it together, and failed to re-apply it after all the paint correction, I made sure to correct that a few days later. I ended up taking 1st in the class, and 2nd on PAX for the event. Tom was 3rd in PAX and we welcomed a newcomer to the St. Louis region, Juan, also in SSC, into the 7th place PAX spot. Juan is down near Springfield, MO and will be joining us for to liven up the competition this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t as productive an event as I would have liked, I always prefer to walk away with a PAX win, but Greer in his GT3 put almost 3/4 of a second in PAX time on me for the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some side by side video of my fastest run (left) and Tom’s fastest run (right).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ntwIlaRbluU&quot; title=&quot;SSC Side By Side Event 1 2021&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;event-2&quot;&gt;Event 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prep for Event 2 only consisted of swapping tires again and the previously mentioned tape work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the event was sloppy, I had a hard time keeping clean and coned my fastest run (first corner before the start lights). Tom ended up taking the win in SSC for the event. I’ll try to get around to videos for that, not sure when I will!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;autocross-settings-from-2021-event-1--2-same-as-2020&quot;&gt;Autocross Settings from 2021 Event 1 &amp;amp; 2 (same as 2020):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Front Swaybar:&lt;/em&gt; Soft setting&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rear Swaybar:&lt;/em&gt; Stiff Setting&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Front Konis:&lt;/em&gt; 0.5 turn from soft&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rear Konis:&lt;/em&gt; 1.5 turns from soft&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Front Tire Pressure:&lt;/em&gt; 30 psi&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rear Tire Pressure:&lt;/em&gt; 29 psi&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 09:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.specfrs.com/2021-events-1-and-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.specfrs.com/2021-events-1-and-2</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020 Season review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;2020, the year that most people want to forget. It started out like any other year, a week into it though I was unemployed, getting let go for the first time in my life (that was’t a bad thing though, trust me). 8 weeks in, the world was starting to wake up to the realization that there was something going on with this virus thing. I was flying to/from Orlando at the end of February. I recall going through the airports thinking that anyone wearing a mask was over reacting, that being said, I wasn’t getting too close to anyone back then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks later I was driving to Stillwater Oklahoma for a bicycle event, waiting for the orange president to come on the air and do a broadcast of what was going on, half expecting to turn around and drive back to St. Louis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went in to 2020 planning to run the FR-S competitively nationally, performning well at the Solo Nationals and then sell the car at the end of the season, ready to move on to something else after 3 seasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The season was cut short, Nationally only attending one event (a win) with the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020-topeka-prosolo-results&quot;&gt;Topeka ProSolo&lt;/a&gt; and I ended up not attending the first two local St. Louis region events as I was concerned with Covid-19 and the risks associated with that. It wasn’t until the third event, June 21st, that I really got out to compete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up attending 7 of 9 St. Louis region events, taking the top PAX (index) finish at 5 of 7 events that I attended. For the year I ended up taking the index championship over Mitchell Coughran, 69,873 out of a possible 70,000 points. For the SSC class I ended up taking 7 of 7 class wins for the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the second time (third if you throw the stupid 2008 double points event out) I took the overall index championship for the St. Louis Region SCCA, the last time being in 2013 in Dave’s street mustang (what was the class back then, rsr?, I really don’t recall).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also awarded the Driver of The Year award for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s next for 2021? Well I ended up deciding not to sell the car. I am signed up for the ProSolo SuperPass, which really doesn’t mean too much other than I get to sign up early for events to make sure I get it. You don’t earn points for the ProSolo Finale this year like in the past, so if you get a ProSolo win, you’re in for the finale, otherwise you might get in by attending enough events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am signed up for the Dixie tour down in southern Georgia in the middle of March, and I will likely run the Topeka ProSolo and possibly Spring Nationals if I don’t do the Unbound Gravel (200 miles) ride in Emporia KS the week after Spring Nationals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local eventwise, I’ll be hitting what events I can. Never say never on trying to repeat with the index championship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2022, who knows, I imagine I will sell the FR-S at the end of this year, but again, never say never.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;autocross-settings-from-2020&quot;&gt;Autocross Settings from 2020:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Front Swaybar:&lt;/em&gt; Soft setting&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rear Swaybar:&lt;/em&gt; Stiff Setting&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Front Konis:&lt;/em&gt; 0.5 turn from soft&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rear Konis:&lt;/em&gt; 1.5 turns from soft&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Front Tire Pressure:&lt;/em&gt; 30 psi&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Rear Tire Pressure:&lt;/em&gt; 29 psi&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 09:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.specfrs.com/2020-season-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.specfrs.com/2020-season-review</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020 Topeka ProSolo Results</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50063439002/in/dateposted/&quot; title=&quot;Conference calls before practice starts&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; alt=&quot;Conference calls before practice starts&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063439002_ae51b1e02e_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;Well that was a productive weekend! I left for Topeka Kansas on Friday morning after working for a few hours and stopped on the drive out for a few more phone calls that I needed to have. I stopped and went into two locations on the drive down, a QuikTrip in Wentzville Missouri, and a Chick-Fil-A in Blue Springs. The QT had no workers or customers (besides myself) wearing a mask. The Chick-Fil-A was still closed for indoor service and all staff were wearing masks while working the drive through lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50062623953/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;SCCA Covid Notices&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;SCCA Covid Notices&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50062623953_55de655c1b_q.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;I was able to get out to Topeka in time get the Falken RT660s mounted on the car and to get some practice starts in with the new starting lights that they have going this year. My first impression of the lights, they change everything. In the olden days for ProSolo, back before LED lights, I used to leave when the second light was &amp;ldquo;going off&amp;rdquo;. With the LED lights introduced in&amp;nbsp; the past couple of years, I would leave when the third light was coming on. With the 2020 version of the lights, I had to wait until the third light was on and then start the process of releasing the clutch to get the car to move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first pass at the lights I turned a .391 reaction time, where a .500 is &amp;ldquo;prefect, and anything less than .500 is RED.&amp;nbsp; My second attempt resulted in a .744, not red, but definitely not in the .5-600 range that I expect when I&amp;rsquo;m starting. My third attempt was a .575 much more respectable. I ended up taking 8 practice starts, and while I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really happy with them, I felt at least comfortable enough for the weekend that I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday night I took the car by the car wash, grabbed a Vegan Lifestyle bowl from Chipotle and ran around to a couple of liquor stores in Topeka looking to add to my whiskey/bourbon collection. Friday night I spent my first night in a hotel with social distancing and cleaning in place. The Hampton Inn had the rooms &amp;ldquo;tapes&amp;rdquo; off with a seal that said they were clean, if the seal was broken you knew it hadn&amp;rsquo;t been cleaned. The elevator had a sign outside of it requesting that only 2 people use an elevator at a time. Overall the hotel experience was great, except for the fact that it was completely full with pre-teens running around on Saturday evening, obviously a sports tournament of some sort brought a lot of kids in, without any masks to be found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50063439742/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Elevator Etiquette&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Elevator Etiquette&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063439742_606cb2d0b6_q.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-right: auto; margin-left: auto; float: none; display: block;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning I walked out of the hotel with the front desk person saying &amp;ldquo;stay dry&amp;rdquo;. I thought, oh it is just a little rain, then the doors parted and I saw that it was a torrential downpour. I navigated out to Heartland Park, going about 45 on the highway due to the conditions and the RT660s feeling a little skatier than I would have liked on the highway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting out to the event site, I was my usual self, the first person out walking the course. By the time I arrived, it was still raining and windy, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t the downpour from the hotel so I walked in just the rain jacket and flip flops for shoes. Went through one area where the standing/running water was a good 2&amp;rdquo; deep, but overall managed to not get myself too soaked. There was plenty of wind damage around the site however.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50063441072/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Saturday morning rain&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Saturday morning rain&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063441072_303dbf889f_q.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50062625818/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Saturday morning carnage&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Saturday morning carnage&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50062625818_81f98a1849_q.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50063184026/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Saturday morning carnage&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Saturday morning carnage&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063184026_1debc7c863_q.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning&amp;rsquo;s start was delayed due to lightning (as was Sundays) but by the time my group ran, it was pretty much dry, with conditions getting better as the morning went on. After the Saturday morning sessions I was sitting in 2nd behind Kinch out of Colorado. Saturday afternoon brought more of the same. I felt I was struggled on the right side course, where I felt a lot more comfortable on the left. Saturday afternoon I found .15 seconds on the left, and just over .3 on the right Saturday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first run on Sunday morning I started on the right and couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any time, but found about .17 on the left, putting me within striking distance of Kinch. My second right side run I hoped I would find another couple of tenths but struggled and was .4 seconds slower than my best attempt on Saturday afternoon. Going into the last right on the left side I was pretty sure that I had no chance, and was going to have to settle for second place behind Kinch. I was pleasantly surprised when I came across on my last run with another .13 second improvement, enough to give me a .052 win over Kinch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first ProSolo win.The car has won previously, multiple times, but for me, in twenty years of autocrossing, this was a first, and it was a blast! Winning your class in a Pro means you move on to the Challenge the second half of Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50063446212/in/album-72157714923533618/&quot; title=&quot;My first christmas tree trophy!&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;My first christmas tree trophy!&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063446212_73b19056a6_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was I believe my fourth attempt at a challenge, and likely the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve moved on passed the first round. I ended up paired up with James Harnish out of Arizona in the first round. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel too great about my runs, but he ended up hitting a cone and that gave me the padding I needed to move on to the next round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Round number 2 I was lined up against Craig Wilcox. I&amp;rsquo;ve known Craig since 2003 or 2004 when we both raced 350Zs in B-Stock. He&amp;rsquo;s out of KC and has multiple national championships under his belt, while I, have none. Sitting at the back of the line waiting for the round to proceed Craig started running around debating on whether or not he needed to get gas for his SMF Honda, I selfishly started wondering if that might not play into my own advantage. It didn&amp;rsquo;t. If anything it took me out of my game. I realized just before pulling to the line that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t set my tire pressures. After round one I had gotten out and check them, but decided to set them closer to running. By the time I realized I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually set them, it was too late, I was strapped in the car and they were getting ready to send us to the line. I tried to put that out of my head and just head on out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first run was once again on the Right side course. I fell asleep at the lights and left with a reaction time of .993 almost half a second off of the ideal reaction time, and three tenths greater than what I would consider acceptable. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel great on the run, but it is also the slower side that I struggled with all weekend, I came back with a 1.001 deficit, almost .5 on the light, and another .6 on the slower course, I felt like that math worked. Going into the left side run I knew I was going to need to push it, and Craig might back off knowing he didn&amp;rsquo;t quite need to push as hard. I left on the last run with a .623 reaction time and pushed as hard as I could to try to find time. I looked across to the other course as I came through the finish and I was quite a bit farther than Craig, I hoped deep down inside that it was enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Craig crossed the line the announcer stated that I had made up over 8 tenths, but not the full second I needed, so I was done and Craig was moving on to the next round against Kinch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the video of my best left and right side runs (Sunday morning and Saturday afternoon respectively). The left side run uses my GoPro Hero8 with stability enabled, on a fixed mount on the roof of the car. The right side run uses the same camera with stability, but on my rotating mount. I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t feel like there is a big difference between the two mounts with the &amp;ldquo;hypersmooth&amp;rdquo; enabled in the GoPro Hero8.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZZk2lKqEbd0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My drive home on Sunday was uneventful, changed tires, loaded up the car, and hit the road. I averaged around 32mpg between Topeka and St. Louis, getting home just after dark so that I could unload the car and see the family before everyone fell asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out additional photos from the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/albums/72157714923533618&quot; title=&quot;2020 Topeka ProSolo&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 Topeka ProSolo&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50063439002_ae51b1e02e_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Autocross Settings:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Swaybar:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Soft setting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Swaybar:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Stiff Setting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Konis:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;0.5 turn from soft&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Konis:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;1.5 turns from soft&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;30&amp;nbsp;psi&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;29&amp;nbsp;psi&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 16:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.specfrs.com/2020-topeka-prosolo-results</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.specfrs.com/2020-topeka-prosolo-results</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020 Solo Spec Coupe (SSC) Falken RT660 Tires</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The time has come, Falken has updated the tire for SSC for 2020 with their latest and greatest Azenis RT660. I&amp;rsquo;ll save you all the story about how there was testing in September (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stay for it), and how they were delayed getting to the states and you have the option of running either the RT-615k or the RT-660 for the 2020 season. All you really need to know is that the RT-660 is a much better tire, and highly recommended (required mostly) if you&amp;rsquo;re running the SSC autocross class with the SCCA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tires are still a great price for SSC (as were the 615ks), I can currently get them from Tire Rack shipped to my door (or favorite installer) for $549!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran my first local event on these tires 2 days ago, and I am still on a euphoric high from their performance and my placement at the top of the PAX/Index results. These tires are a huge upgrade over the 615ks. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the 615ks, I feel they served as a great tire for 2 years in the infancy of the Solo Spec Coupe class, but the 660s are so much more. They are sticky. They are fun, they are competitive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the rest of the 2020 season and have gone ahead and booked myself into the Topeka ProSolo this weekend in Kansas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a video from our fastest run, Run #6, at the event, using our JD1 Camera Mount with a new GoPro Hero 8 Black&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0sm0iK9IifU&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Autocross Settings:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Swaybar:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Soft setting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Swaybar:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Stiff Setting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Konis:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;0.5 turn from soft&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Konis:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;1.5 turns from soft&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;30&amp;nbsp;psi&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;29&amp;nbsp;psi&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.specfrs.com/2020-solo-spec-coupe-ssc-falken-rt660-tires</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.specfrs.com/2020-solo-spec-coupe-ssc-falken-rt660-tires</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2019 SpecFRS.com Season up to Nationals</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BwS-GexFfU8/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BwS-GexFfU8/&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BwS-GexFfU8/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by SpecFRS (@specfrs)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-04-16T00:32:09+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 15, 2019 at 5:32pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where has the time gone? The 2019 season, at least Nationally, has come, and almost gone. The ProSolo Finale and TireRack National Championships are next week in Lincoln Nebraska, and SpecFRS.com will be there. But how did we get there? Let’s look back on the 2019 season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The season started out in with a test and tune in St. Louis on March 10th. To start the season off, Sean Greer was planning on running the car, so we took it to Family Arena and tried to work off the rust (from the drivers). We followed up the test and tune with a local event in St. Louis at the end of March, with Chris taking the win in SSC and Sean taking second, in the three car class. It would be June 9th before we had another local event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April brought the first ProSolo for the year, in Grenada Mississippi. Sean and I headed down through Memphis on Friday, stopping to buy some, only available in Tennessee, Jack Daniel’s bottles to add to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.CollectorOfJack.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CollectorOfJack.com&lt;/a&gt; site. Grenada had 14 drivers in the class, with 5 trophies. Chris took the 5th and final trophy spot with Sean taking third for the event, each of them besting the other on one side of the 2 sided ProSolo courses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next was Lincoln Nebraska in late May for the Spring Nationals Champ Tour and ProSolo. In the ProSolo there were 16 drivers, 5 trophies. Chris managed to take 4th, while Sean finished in 8th for the Pro. The Lincoln Champ tour had 14 drivers, 5 trophies, with both Chris and Sean finishing in the trophies. Chris in 2nd, behind Kevin Dietz and Sean in 5th. Chris managed to pull out his best runs the last run each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Lincoln, Sean was pretty put off by the car, and decided that he wouldn’t be running it much going forward. Chris jumped straight into the local event scene and found success in 3 of the next 4 events, taking the SSC class win in all but one. At event #3 Tom Sotitopoulos, who co-drive last year, jumped in the car for the remainder of the season. In event 4 he managed to best Chris to take the class win. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 4 more local events this year, as of right now Chris is holding down the class lead in points, and is setting in second place in PAX/Index for the year. With this difficult PAX number, it will be hard to take the index win for the year, but that is the ultimate goal, Chris trying to repeat what he did in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here we are, heading to Lincoln on Friday, towing the car down with a fresh set of Falken tires and the alignment reset our specs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing we’ve changed this season is to adjusted air pressures down a bit in the back, from 31/31 to 31/30. No other changes from the car as to what we ran for settings last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Autocross Settings used 2019:&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Swaybar: &lt;/strong&gt;Soft setting&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Swaybar:&lt;/strong&gt; Stiff Setting&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Konis:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.5 turn from soft&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Konis:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.5 turns from soft&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; 31 psi&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rear Tire Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; 30 psi&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brake Pads:&lt;/strong&gt; Ferodo DS2500	&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 03:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.specfrs.com/2019-specfrscom-season-up-to-nationals</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.specfrs.com/2019-specfrscom-season-up-to-nationals</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
        <category>Setup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SpecFRS at the 2018 ProSolo Finale</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is coming 6 months (maybe more?) too late, but at least it is coming. The 2018 ProSolo Finale and Solo National Championships was a week of ups and downs for the team. The results were mixed across the board in terms of performance with some highlights and some down times as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off the week we arrived for the ProSolo Finale on Friday, got the car off the trailer and waited for things to dry so that we could get some practice starts in on a drying start line. Everyone was waiting for dry conditions, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if that was going to happen, so I went out and took some starts to try to get a feel for the brand new Falkens that were on the car. Teddy took a couple of starts as well before the mad rush of people. The car needed some decals applied before everything got started, but overall was ready for the week of events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning for the ProSolo Finale came with Teddie heading out in L4. She struggled on Saturday morning with red light and cone runs, but putting her fastest left side run down for the weekend on her 2nd attempt. I also went out with Red Light and Cone issues on my first runs on each side. On the 2nd attempt on the right side I laid down my fastest run, it was about 7/10ths off the pace needed for the class for the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday afternoon both Teddie and I were able to put down faster runs on the other side, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t quite make up the differences we wanted. Sunday morning it was wet and cold and barely anyone found time on the course, Teddie and myself finding none.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teddie ended up in 3rd in L4 (ssc) for the weekend, 1 out of trophies, but close enough to get into the ladies challenge bracket on Sunday afternoon. I on the other hand ended up in 14th place, out of 18 drivers, well over 2 seconds off the pace. To say I was displeased with my performance is an understatement. I spent the next few days wondering why I was going to stay in Lincoln for the next 5 days for the Solo Nationals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday afternoon was a definite bright spot for the ProSolo Finale, Teddie ended up in the Ladies challenge and performed very well! She ended up making it to the semi final round before being knocked into the third place bracket. She ended up taking Third place to help salvage the weekend for both of us! I also headed out with my camera and shot a lot of the ProSolo challenge, having the most fun I had all weekend behind the lens of my camera. You can check out some of the photos via the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gallery links over on RainbowMarks.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/30715031998/in/album-72157701162224125/&quot; title=&quot;Ladies Challenge - ProSolo Finale 2018&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ladies Challenge - ProSolo Finale 2018&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; src=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1848/30715031998_f8bfc33bb7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 04:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.specfrs.com/specfrs-at-the-2018-prosolo-finale</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.specfrs.com/specfrs-at-the-2018-prosolo-finale</guid>
        
        
        <category>Autocross</category>
        
        <category>Toyota</category>
        
        <category>FR-S</category>
        
        <category>SSC</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
